How worried do we need to be about the
market absolutely collapsing and taking
a big dumply doodla on bond yields which
just keep going up and why do they keep
going up and what is the underlying
economy saying and what again are the
canaries in the coal mine because so far
we have been probably honestly too
bullish on the NASDAQ 100. We were so
bullish on the NASDAQ 100, we sent out
uh a lot of talk in our alpha reports
and our morning course member live
streams on the NASDAQ 100 going straight
up to all-time new highs that we were so
bullish. We pointed out specifically the
712 October 16 calls probably about a
month ago at this point somewhere around
it was around September 14thish
somewhere around there. Right while we
were in the midst of the tanker for
tanker strikes, this option has
literally gone from around 12 bucks over
here all the way to $44.
That's almost a four freaking Xer on
this option. Why? What is going on? What
are the underlying pros and cons to this
economy? And what's going on with those
credit spreads and bonds? We're going to
talk about it. Uh first quick note, come
join us over at what is now called
Reinvest One. That is our product where
you get everything we have to offer. The
alpha membership, all the trade alerts,
so the alpha report you get every single
morning before the market opens up, the
course member live streams, the trade
alerts, that's all in there. Then we've
got a huge terminal release coming
towards the end of this year that is
going to include the totally rebuilt
reinvest stocks platform. Beautiful
little coming soon right here. The
home's AI release is included in that.
All nine courses, the course member live
streams, and a product for uh agents for
consumers and agents for business.
That'll all be included in Q1 and Q2.
So, we got a lot of cool things coming
that is all available in one
subscription. Actually, it's a one-time
payment. So, it's a lifetime payment.
That's why we call it reinvest one. You
pay once. And uh in 2027, new people
will have to pay it as a subscription,
but if you get in before then, it'll be
a lifetime access product for you, which
we think is very exciting. That said,
let's get into what's going on with
yields and the economy. So, right now,
the economy, as we know, is cooking a
lot. We just got the S&P f uh S&P global
uh final read for September, and we also
got the uh PMI final read from the ISMS.
And uh we have two main canaries that
we've been talking about on the channel
and a lot of people get a little
confused when I talk about these
canaries because you know they wonder is
it really these two and the answer is
yes. So we are certainly seeing an
insane boom in artificial intelligence
spending right now. There's no question
of that. In fact we have the technology
sector accelerating its growth to its
fastest pace in over 5 years. We're
basically comparing to 2021,
which is kind of crazy because if we're
comparing to 2021,
we're comparing to like boom time and
we're saying we're going the fastest
since then, which everything between
then and now has been getting crushed by
the growth the economy is seeing right
now. A lot of it because of artificial
intelligence spend and what's becoming
more and more ubiquitous use. People and
businesses not using AI are really
getting left behind. That leaves us with
two main canaries. The one canary in the
coal mine that does not change its color
or its style or anything is the labor
market. The labor market's ability to
absorb layoffs and sort of the
rejiggering
is what keeps all of this boom going.
The labor market rolls over, we're all
cooked. The economy falls off a cliff.
So, this is why paying attention to
what's going on in the labor market is
very important. Fortunately, if we look
at a three and six-month trend of both
the ADP private payrolls report, which
is sort of our fact check on the
government data, and the 3 to sixmonth
trend on the government data, we can
actually see the economyy's kind of
picking up when it comes to employment.
I mean, look at Nick T's posts on X.
You've got right here the three and six
month payrolls growth levels plus
private sector payrolls growth. We've
kind of hit this floor in 2025 during
that immigration era. A lot of
nervousness that labor was going to go
pretty negative here and we've really
rebounded off of this. As long as we
don't plummet off this cliff, something
starts reversing course over here. The
labor canary is doing good for now,
which is great. It lets us stay bullish
on the economy. And we're seeing this
here in the ISM reports that came out
this morning, filling positions that
have been vacated due to promotions or
retiring. That's still happening. We've
got employment returning to expansion in
September and we've got restructuring
due to efficiency gains using AI. So the
fact that you have restructuring going
on, it's still employment gains. So far
so good. And the second canary is what I
call the underwriters of the AI trade.
That's currently opening.
Those could be different in the future.
You might swap out who underwrites the
purchases of AMD chips and Nvidia chips
via either NBIS or Coreweave or SpaceX
or you know whatever it doesn't really
matter through Microsoft right it
doesn't matter so much who the
underlying is it matters who the end
user is and the end user right now is or
buyer is open AI anthropic on behalf of
you and businesses so the end user of
those chips core canary in the coal mine
now good news is in two or three years.
Those might be hot swappable. You know,
there could be a new company. I don't
know. It could be reinvest and it takes
over from OpenAI and Anthropic,
whatever. Point is, it could be a
different company. And the benefit of
that is that canary can evolve. The
labor market can't. So, watching both of
those is the most important factor going
forward. But, I mean, Microsoft is a
fantastic play as well. We have a uh
price target that we've been talking
about for quite a while uh in our course
member live streams of 562 for
Microsoft. I encourage you to join us
there. Join us at meetke.com. With that,
you pay once you get lifetime access to
everything. Uh and so Microsoft has been
been crushing it and I think they're
quietly breaking out. People aren't
paying attention to that breakout that's
coming for Microsoft. But consider some
of these notes here and then we need to
look at some of the more maybe
concerning or dare we say the more
nervous pieces about the acceleration
that's cooking in yields. But if we go
to this S&P here, we can see there's a
sharp upturn that we're seeing in the
technology sector. All seven US sectors
posted expansion of business activity
during September. The majority saw
stronger growth than in August.
Technology was by far the best
performing category at 62.7 in
September, up from 56.6 in August. The
sharpest rate of business activity
expansion since June of 2021. September
data also indicated the steepest rise in
input prices. Now, that's unfortunate.
That obviously weighs on what we're
seeing with Treasury yields, which
Treasury yields in fairness right now at
about 5.32.
It's about five basis points above sort
of my ideal like ah this is where we
should really stop going up because
you're eventually going to break
something. And that's exactly why you've
got academy securities
nervous. Not only is it this yield
getting back to uh or the spread between
the twos and the 10 getting back to 50
which is shock territory. She doesn't
necessarily guarantee you're going to
get a shock. Right? We sat over 50 from
liberation day through basically the end
of the well the original ceasefire you
were above sha sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh
sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh sh
sh sh sh sh sh sh shock territory. So it
doesn't necessarily guarantee you're
going to have a shock, but it does
indicate that the risks are higher. And
that's where Academy Securities gives us
a little bit of color where they
actually towards the end of their
article, they argue that look, a deal
with Iran and more news on AI, all that
can help. Duh. We already know Kevin's
bullish on a deal with Iran. That's
bullish for the market. The market, you
know, the market's going to go up and
people are going to go look back at this
market and they're going to say, "Wait,
how did it just go from 700 to 800 on
the cues? It's going to happen in like a
blink of an eye." It's the same thing
with Nvidia. You know, I've been bullish
this uh 227 breakout on Nvidia and it's
now at 237. We are starting the very
breakout we have been calling for, baby.
At the same time, even Marll has been
breaking out of our 266 line that we've
been watching pretty heavily. So, with
that said, they do say calmly nervous,
not scared. Now, why are they nervous?
Because they're nervous due to this
widening that we're seeing in higher
yield credit. Now, we've talked about
this last week as well. A lot of people
have been talking about these spreads
widening. And when you zoom out,
they're not horrible in the context of
themselves. When we zoom out on the high
yield spreads, yes, they have widened,
which is a risk for the economy. Are
they higher relative to what we saw in
2022, for example? No.
But one of the reasons they're spreading
or things are even worse now, if you
will, is because that nominal yield on
the 10-year Treasury is so damn high and
the market is just blatantly ignoring
it. This is what makes this individual
nervous and I think rightfully so. And
they give us a little bit of color into
where they think retail is buying versus
where the suits are not paying
attention. So, I'm going to show you
that in just a moment. I think that's
quite interesting. But a lot of people
ask me, hey, when this nonsense happens,
we touched on this also this morning in
our course member liveream. I'll just
make a quick little note on this. Uh
people often say like Kevin, you know,
how how do you allocate in this? Like
how do you hedge if you have a little
pie that you invest into stocks? How do
you hedge yourself against some kind of
panic? And so my thesis is that what you
do is sort of like a little electrical
circuit. You take money that you earn
and you have this little resistor and
the resistor limits how much money you
throw into the stock market. I think the
allocation is the way that you hedge. In
other words, you could be a really big
bull on your stock portfolio, but maybe
out of every $100 of investable capital
you have, you're only putting, you know,
maybe 30% into this. And then maybe
you're putting some into private equity,
some into real estate, some into debt
payoff, some into cash, right? And so
this is really a way that you could
hedge. All of these become a hedge to
the stock market. It's not saying stocks
are bad. You could be bullish on stocks.
I mean, heck, we are. This is why we've
been buying the dip and and sending out
trade alerts at 700 on the cues going,
"No, man. This is bull crap. This is
peak fear." And people still I I'll see
the comments. People like, "But Kevin, I
thought you said peak fear was 3 weeks
ago." I go, "Look at the cues 3 weeks
ago." It just made us straight up from
there. But anyway, uh look at this. This
is the uh 10 year. And what they were
talking about here is this acceleration
is being ignored by the stock market and
it creates risks. Right? The slope of
the line was already aggressive over
here, also aggressive here, but the
slope has gone nuts over here. That
increase in the slope creates a lot of
potential risk for the economy. Hence us
being at this this sort of shock
territory. Uh now an interesting note
that they say is they say there are no
treasury bears. Like anytime you talk to
people they're not bearish on
treasuries. In fact they say that retail
is probably early and beating the pros
again by throwing inflows like crazy
into TLT. TLT has received the largest
inflows and it's now at the highest
level since late 2024. Now TLT is really
interesting because it's now losing my
bottom line over here. You can see the
last time this happened was in October
and November of 2023 and we usually tend
to bounce bounce bounce bounce bounce
bounce right uh off of this 7877 line.
We're under that right now.
This author argues that retail is early
at buying the dip on bonds, but also
says there are no bond bears. Like
people are either neutral or bullish on
bond yields. So why are are are bonds
losing value? Why are yields going up?
Well, he says because of the following.
The price of oil is bearish for bonds.
The deficit is bearish for bonds.
Long-term treasuries uh issuance is
bearish for bonds. the global supply, so
every country's issuance of bonds is
bearish. Corporate supply, uh, so how
much, you know, SpaceX has to suck money
or Google has to suck money. That's also
bearish. Google just did a preferred.
Maybe you didn't hear about it, but it's
worth knowing. Google just did a
preferred.
they raised, I think it was at a 6.5%
preferred
uh stock deal where you earn 6 and a
half%
between now and the summer of 2029. So
basically they pay you six and a half% a
year for three years and then that
either gets uh I'm I'm sure if it's
mandatory convertible. I'd have to look.
But basically it it converts into Google
stock at like $440 or something like
that. Now I personally think that's a
bad deal. Uh and you should look up the
details yourself. I personally think
it's a bad deal because it converts at a
premium and Google's at like $340 right
now, [laughter] you know. So you're
build you're already building in a lot
of upside. I think that deal would have
been a lot more fair if they ran it at
it's 6 12% for 3 years, but we're giving
you the option to get in basically at
the stock at 340 bucks or 360 bucks, you
know, somewhere over here. Not such a
massive premium, but whatever. That's
just an example more sucking. and the
fact that countries like Saudi Arabia or
if you include what I said, Japan uh and
Europe selling US treasuries, you've got
a lot of people basically getting rid of
treasuries because they need to raise
money themselves, not because they're
bearish on a 5.3% 10-year Treasury
yield. It's just because they have other
needs. They got to fund the AI buildout,
whatever. So in other words, they argue
that right now is a time to be maybe
cautious slash nervous
but not fearful. And I think that really
kind of puts together how this market
feels because people are so nervous
about this economy and yet the economy
keeps impressing to the upside. And if
we look at the copper to gold ratio,
this is basically uh take the rising
price of copper which has been
performing very well. It's an industrial
metal and compare it to gold. Uh and uh
typically uh what well first of all we
can pinpoint over here that the bottom
was basically when wash was chosen which
is really interesting because even if
you hold copper stable and gold prices
come down gold is a fear metal. So as
fear in that case goes down this chart
goes up. So you could say that oh this
chart is getting higher which you know
if gold goes down and then copper goes
up as well that spread widens so the
chart goes up even more. Generally you
say as the chart goes up the economy
feels more bullish but it's been coming
after this plummeting of the chart which
was really gold rising.
So uh because copper has been been doing
very decently the past few years. So,
let's chart that out like this and it's
going to make a little bit more sense
here.
Okay. So, this downtrend right here has
pretty much been driven by gold rising.
Okay, so this would be gold rising. Uh
now if we look at
the trend over here on the right, gold
stopped here
due to WH. Remember on January 30th I
predicted that the top was in for gold
because Kevin Walsh is not a money
printer fed chair. That's bad for a
future recession. And it's also bearish
gold. I think gold is going to be in an
eight-year bare market because Kevin
Walsh is at the helm of the Fed. So
that's me taking my studying from the
Fed and applying it to gold. Now this
section that we're getting right here is
actually being this sort of uptrend
right here. This is not driven much by
gold in my opinion or as much by gold. I
think this is being driven driven by
copper and driven by the economy. So
basically economic boom. Now you could
explain this chart however but I think
this helps putting perspective on why
this chart is moving like this. And what
we're finding is we're actually now
reversing a 5-year downtrend in the
copper to gold ratio. And it's possible
if the economy keeps booming like this
line could actually be substantially
higher in the future. Z even if gold
just stays stable, copper could keep
moving.
Uh okay. And if copper stops moving,
gold can fall. E either way, the the
spread is often a bar barometer of the
economy. And my take is that the spread
continues to widen e in spite of the
fears regarding the treasury market. So
going back for a moment on the
underlying economy, the underlying
economy on S&P data that we got this
morning indicates that industrials are
outperforming, consumer services
maintained a strong bis maintain strong
business activities uh activity and even
financials which came down and saw a
loss of their growth momentum are still
expanding faster than they did in the
first half of the year. So in other
words, even where things are not doing
as well are still doing very well.
Healthcare was the weakest sector though
they did admit. So all of this together
does suggest an economy that's booming
on AI spend and we do have these two
real risks. Could we incorporate a
credit crisis into this? It's possible.
I mean I always think like I say you
want to sort of the way you hedge is you
allocate to different things outside of
the stock market. But I think trying to
hedge for that black swan is a really
complicated thing to do and you'll
probably get the timing wrong. So this
is why I prefer the two canaries for
determining
what issues we have in the economy. As
long as these two canaries are kicking
butt, which both of them are, then we
should be bullish stocks. And that's
what we're seeing. That's why I think we
continue to drive uh all-time highs on
the cues. And as you know, maybe
unpopular as an opinion as it is, you
know, I think the rise in Meta, uh, the
rise in Microsoft, the NASDAQ 100,
Nvidia, all this stuff is just at the
beginning. Well, I shouldn't say the
beginning, but it's still ahead of the
big euphoria to come, which to me is
very exciting. Uh and if you want to see
exactly, you know, what trades we're
making, how we're positioning our uh
research uh platform that's [music]
coming later this year, the reinvest
terminal, you want to be part of that
before we get rid of lifetime [music]
access. You can lock that in uh before
the end of the year. And then, of
course, we'll have price increases uh
coming between now and the end of the
year, so you'll still have the best
price [music] if you join today versus
later the year. But anyway, check that
out over at meetke.com. I think it's a
really great product and [music] what
we're building is really, really
exciting. So, we'd love to have you as
part of it. If you like that video,
check this one out. I think you're going
to love it.
>> Why not advertise these [music] things
that you told us here? I feel like
nobody else knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Praath there, financial analyst
[music] and YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always
great to get your take.